Jess Pates

Fullstack Developer

Profile

Driven, reliable and conscientious individual; recently completed a fullstack Web Development course at Le Wagon after ten years experience working within financial services operations. Aptitude for numerical work with an enjoyment of problem solving and analytical thinking. Strong and approachable team player - displayed and improved in multiple workplaces with varying cultures. Enthusiastic and keen learner, always seeking new challenges and opportunities for self-improvement as demonstrated by recent career change. Looking to bring skills gained in the workplace alongside the knowledge rapidly acquired through the Web Development bootcamp to a new position as a Fullstack Developer.

Education

Web Development Bootcamp, Le Wagon 9-week full-time intensive coding bootcamp learning HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript ES6, SQL, git, GitHub, Heroku and Ruby on Rails.	Oct 2022 – Dec 2022
BSc Economics 2:1, University of Nottingham	Sep 2008 – Jul 2011
A Level: 3 A; AS Level: 2 A; GCSE: 9 A*, 3 A, Manchester High School for Girls	Sep 2001 – Jul 2008
Projects	

Projects

Fan Find 🛮

A Ruby on Rails mobile website using HTML, CSS and Javascript to bring together football fans from different countries through events based on World Cup games. Created as part of a team during Le Wagon bootcamp.

shART

An AirBnB clone for the sharing and lending of artwork. Created as part of a team during Le Wagon bootcamp.

Watchlist

Ruby on Rails site for organising movies into lists based on genre.

Skills

Ruby on Rails | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | GitHub | SQL | Javascript | Excel

Professional Experience

Operations Associate, *Symmetry Investments*

Jul 2019 - Aug 2022

Thrived working within surroundings that encouraged autonomy and became go to person for certain operations functions. Took initiative to streamline processes and make them more efficient, working with experienced developers and leveraging their knowledge.

Operations Analyst, Capula Investment Management

Oct 2017 – May 2019

Reconciled large volumes of trades and positions in environment with no margin for error. Collaborated with others on projects such as fund launches and system improvements. Maintained calm temperament and clear thinking in often stressful surroundings.

Operations Analyst, Dalton Strategic Partnership

Jun 2014 – Jul 2017

Worked within a small team and quickly acquired knowledge and responsibility in a new field. Gained experienced in full range of operations functions, building valuable relationships with both internal and external contacts.

Corporate Actions Senior Specialist, BNY Mellon

Aug 2012 - Jun 2014

Responsible for checking and approving the work of others in a high risk role with demanding deadlines. Required high attention to detail and clear, regular communication.

Interests